
 const   qbank = [
    {
        question: 'Write an elevator pitch for G Adventures formerly known as GAP Tours OR for 7 Virtues Perfume.',
        answer: `G Adventures: Are you looking to change people's lives through travel, while having the time of your life? G Adventures offers experience-craving travellers an alternative to typical expensive and boring trips through community tourism. We create meaningful relationships with local communities, directly benefiting the people and places we visit. With over 10 unique travel styles, 100% guaranteed departures, and over 93 worldwide destinations, G Adventures can ensure that you'll experience a once-in-a-lifetime trip, while creating a positive social impact throughout your journey.

        7 Virtues Perfume: Are you looking to shop for perfume while helping those in need at the same time? Our 7 Virtues Perfume is more than just a fragrance brand, it's a movement to use business for peace and the money we use to source our legal orange blossoms are used to empower the economy in Afghanistan. Our $100 value perfume will not only help you make your money back, but you get to make a bigger impact on the world with just one spray.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Using only Value Innovation theory, explain the success of Cirque du Soleil.',
        answer: `Value innovation is the simultaneous pursuit of differentiation and low cost. Guy Laliberte's concept, nurtured in Europe, involved creating a circus that did not employ animals in its performances, even though the big draw for traditional circuses has always been the animals. Cirque du Soleil value innovated by shifting the buyer group from children (end-users of the traditional circus) to adults (purchasers of the traditional circus). Guy saw the possibilities to reinvent the industry and created a new market space by challenging the conventional assumptions about how to compete. Cirque du Soleil changed the nature of what a circus show looks like; thus, decreasing significant costs common to the industry. As well, Cirque du Soleil increased value to the buyer by offering customers innovative shows that can be watched in different locations; consequently, increasing demand. Drawing upon the distinctive strengths of existing alternatives to offer a new and innovative experience, Guy was able to launch his ambitious venture with a clear vision, specifically a blue-ocean vision. `
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the difference between a manager and a leader? Give one example that illustrates the difference.',
        answer: `The difference between a manager and a leader is that leaders have personal power while managers have positional power. An example that illustrates this difference is that leaders inspire and lead their team to success and have people follow them while managers have subordinates and dictate tasks to see problems resolved fast. Additionally, managers are scared of change and tell their teams to “do as I say”, versus a leader who isn't afraid of change, rather they make and embrace change and tell their team to “do as I do”.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the “Bus theory” from Good to Great?',
        answer: `The Bus Theory (also known as the first who theory) revolves around first getting the right people on the bus (and the wrong people off the bus). The right people are those who can adapt easier to a changing world and appreciate being on the bus with the other right people, they are self-motivated to be part of something great, and they are not the wrong people (e.g., if you have the wrong people, it doesn't matter if you discover the right direction).`
    },
    {
        question: `Explain Walmart's Hedgehog concept.`,
        answer: `Passionate - Low Everyday Pricing; 
        Best in the world - know they can be the best, if you work on developing your best competencies; 
        Economic engine - Buying things for cheaper had the biggest impact`
    },
    {
        question: `The Lean Startup applies the scientific method to entrepreneurship, including the use of hypothesis testing. A good hypothesis must be 4 things. Name and explain them.`,
        answer: `Must be written down in advance - structuring your hypotheses: “I (or we) believe…”
        Be falsifiable - Is there a test after which the hypothesis could turn out to be wrong? If not, it's not a falsifiable hypothesis or in other words: It's not really a hypothesis
        Be testable - can your hypothesis be experimented? 
        Be quantifiable`
    },
    {
        question: `Twenty years ago, startups focused on raising investment. What do founders today focus on instead? Why don't they focus on investment early anymore?`,
        answer: `Today, it's a lot cheaper to start a business, so there is less risk attached. Investment early on simply isn't as necessary. Instead of focusing on investors we now focus on customers. Today, customers are seen greater than investors because customers can provide you with vital feedback. Consequently, customers provide traction and validation. Finally, customers can help market your product through social media (e.g., reviews, tutorials, word of mouth, affiliate marketing) more than an investor.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Why must you “get out of the building”?',
        answer: `Coined by Steve Blank, “get out of the building” refers to getting to know your customers in their own environment, mainly for startups. Moreover, this concept helps a startup better understand their customers' wants and needs to build a product that they want, versus not what the business thinks they want. “Get out of the building” avoids making assumptions and uses market research to determine product features, marketing channels, and distribution models. By speaking with potential customers will a startup understand if there's a gap in the market for them to fill with a new product.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Name the 5 KPIs that make up Pirate Metrics. Instead of defining them, show how Uber might use each.',
        answer: `Acquisition: downloading the app and signing up for an account for the first-time. 
        Activation: requesting a ride service to take you from point A to point B.  
        Retention: customers become 'repeat riders' by continuing to order a ride service via the Uber app.
        Referral: Using referral codes (e.g., free ride/$20 coupon) that customers can send to friends. 
        Revenue: the money that Uber makes when a customer completes a ride/transaction.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the difference between problem/solution fit and product/market fit? Which boxes on the Lean Canvas relate to each?',
        answer: `Problem-solution fit is about finding a problem worth solving. You know you've found PSF because you start generating revenue; therefore, proving that people want your solution. This would fit into the Problem, Solution, Customer Segments, and UVP boxes on the Lean Canvas. 

        Product-market fit proves you have an efficient business, one that can make lots of revenue each time a new customer is added even though the cost to add that customer is small. This could fit in the Revenue, Cost Structures, Key Channels, and Unfair Advantage boxes on the Lean Canvas.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What are the three (3) risks startups should try to mitigate?',
        answer: `1. 	Management Risk
        2.	Market Risk
        3.	Magic Risk`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the Stockdale Paradox? What does it teach entrepreneurs?',
        answer: `The Stockdale Paradox explains that you must maintain unwavering faith that you can and will prevail in the end, regardless of the difficulties, and at the same time, have the discipline to confront the most brutal facts of your current reality, whatever they might be. The Stockdale Paradox teaches entrepreneurs grounded optimism. `
    },
    {
        question: `A business you have invested in is struggling. It's time for the founder to step aside and a new CEO to take over. Would you apply bottom up or top-down hiring? Why? What are the advantages of that method? Why not use the other method?`,
        answer: `You would apply top-down hiring in this scenario. This is because Top-Down Hiring is used when a company is looking for top executives or people with experience in the industry to join the team to bring in new leadership and management. Using top-down hiring helps bring in fresh vantage points, steals competitor leaders, and they come with experience and insights about the industry that you may not know. It's not ideal to use bottom-up hiring here because sometimes they don't have new ideas and this approach only hires specific people with specific skills and experience to fill a specific role.`
    },
    {
        question: `Why does it cost more hire 9s? Why is it worth it? Does it really cost more?`,
        answer: `The reason it costs more to hire 9s is because they are regarded as the 'superstars'; in other words, 9s are more efficient because they know what they are doing. Also, 9s have internal locus of control, they are motivated to work, and determined to achieve a successful result. It's worth hiring 9s because those who are 9's don't need to be babysat - they are hardworking, action-oriented and motivate those around them as well. It'll cost you more to hire 6s than 9s since those who are 6s need direction and training on how to perform certain tasks, but also firing expenses add up more than what it costs to hire 9s on your team. `
    },
    {
        question: 'When is a startup no longer a startup?',
        answer: `When it is ready to scale, it has found product market fit, it knows the lifetime value of a new customer far exceeds cost of customer acquisition, when the business model is fully known, and when the lean canvas has no more assumptions to test.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Name and explain the 3 corners of the Timmons Model.',
        answer: `The opportunity - determine if there is a clear customer need or is the timing right: team ready, market ready?
        The entrepreneur - does the entrepreneur have the experience within the proposed industry? Investors prefer to see a track record of driving growth and profits.
        The resources - Capital, technology, equipment, and people; find ways to get things done faster, cheaper or better`
    },
    {
        question: 'Define and explain the 10x Rule. Give an example of how Netflix demonstrates the 10x rule.',
        answer: `The 10x Rule states that you must be 10x cheaper, smaller, faster, and more efficient compared to current market trends to overcome and creatively destroy the incumbents. An example is Netflix and how their platform destroyed Blockbuster's business model.`
    },
    {
        question: 'List 4 criteria for a great Elevator Pitch:',
        answer: `Irrefutable - pain statement should not be subjective
        Greed inducing - should illustrate how an investor can make money
        Easily understandable - simple enough that both an investor and your grandmother can understand
        Succinct - short enough to be said in 3-4 sentences or 1-2 minutes`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the definition of a startup?',
        answer: `A startup is a novel organization that is searching for a sustainable, repeatable, scalable business model.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Define Adversity Quotient.',
        answer: `The adversity quotient is one of the main characteristics of an entrepreneur., It can be defined as the measure of someone's resilience and ability to keep persevering in the face of adversity, uncertainty, or failure.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Define Internal Locus of Control.',
        answer: `Having an internal locus of control refers to the way entrepreneurs perceive their external environment and the power they have over it. In other words, it's having a strong desire to be in control of your own fate.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What are the four essential qualities of any true opportunity?',
        answer: 'Timely, durable, attractive, customer-centric'
    },
    {
        question: 'Define Social Entrepreneurship.',
        answer: `A social entrepreneur is someone who recognizes a social problem or need, comes up with a solution (10x solution) and creates an organization to pursue it.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is dilution?',
        answer: `Dilution is the decrease in existing shareholders' ownership as a result of an injection of capital.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What are the three dimensions of the Hedgehog Concept?',
        answer: `When you find the intersection of what you're passionate about, what you can be the best in the world at, and what best drives your economic engine.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Which entrepreneurs are known to have a quadruple bottom line?',
        answer: 'Indigenous Entrepreneurs'
    },
    {
        question: 'The Talent Triangle consists of three elements, what are they?',
        answer: `Business Acumen
        Operational Excellence
        Domain Knowledge`
    },
    {
        question: 'When growing a business, an entrepreneur can hire in one of two ways. What are they?',
        answer: `1. Top-down hiring
        2. Bottom-up hiring 
        `
    },
    {
        question: 'Tom from Mississauga is looking to raise $200,000. He is willing to give up 10%. What would the post-money valuation be if his deal was accepted?',
        answer: `$2,000,000`
    },
    {
        question: 'Stefan is looking to raise money on a $1 million post-money valuation. He accepts a deal from Mr. Wonderful for 30% of his company. What is his pre-money valuation?',
        answer: `$700,000`
    },
    {
        question: `Jennifer goes to Dragons' Den and offers the investors 20% equity stake in return for $80,000 cash. What is the pre-money valuation?`,
        answer: `$320,000`
    },
    {
        question: `Joan and Sal founded ABC Electric as equal partners with $50,000 of their own money. A year later they receive $80,000 from Joan's mother for a 20% equity stake in the company. How much of the company's equity does Joan own?`,
        answer: `40%`
    },
    {
        question: `Joan and Sal founded ABC Electric as equal partners. In year one, they received funding from Joan's mother who has a 20% stake in the company. Recently, they accepted an offer from a VC for 30% of the company. How much would Sal own after the deal?`,
        answer: `28%`
    },
    {
        question: 'Define Level V leadership.',
        answer: `Level 5 leader is best described as an enlightened leader that has personal power based on humility and pride. (Level 5 Leader = Humility + Will). More importantly, it's leading change instead of having change lead you. Level 5 Leaders can channel their ego away from themselves and into the larger goal of building a great company. It's not that level 5 leaders have no ego or self-interest. Indeed, they are incredibly ambitious — but their ambition is first and foremost for the business, not themselves. `
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the S-Curve and what does it illustrate?',
        answer: `The S-Curve is a model of new market product adoption. It illustrates the lifecycle of a startup up.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is the difference between a blue-ocean strategy and a red-ocean strategy?',
        answer: `A Blue Ocean Strategy refers to a company creating uncontested market space that makes competitors irrelevant (the simultaneous pursuit of differentiation and low cost). Whereas, a Red Ocean Strategy is when companies try to outperform their rivals to grab a greater share of existing demand.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What are the four actions framework?',
        answer: 'Eliminate, raise, create, and reduce'
    },
    {
        question: 'What is microfinancing?',
        answer: `Microfinancing has made it much easier for people who only need a small loan to kick start their business. An example of this is Kiva.org which is an online microfinancing platform that allows people to choose who they want to invest in; thus, simplifying the lending process.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Write an A/B Test for Wikipedia',
        answer: `Group A (50% of users): The site search bar increased visual prominence and altered the placeholder text to say "Search Wikipedia”, and the search function searched multiple links and filtered the results with those keywords.

        Group B (50% of users): The search bar had increased visual prominence, the placeholder text was altered to "Search by topic," and the search function directed the user immediately to that page, rather than listing other potential filtered search results.
        `
    },
    {
        question: 'What does the 10/20/30 rule say?',
        answer: `That you must have 10 slides, 20 minutes, 30 point font.`
    },
    {
        question: `You and your business partner equally own Startup X.  You accept an investment from your Aunt Agatha for $30,000 on a pre-money valuation of $70,000.  After the deal is done, how much do you own?`,
        answer: `35%`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is bootstrapping?',
        answer: `Bootstrapping is using only your own money and sales to fund a business`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is premature scaling?',
        answer: `Premature scaling is when you grow your business before you should. It is also when entrepreneurs are too focused on one dimension of the business and advancing it out of sync with the rest of their operations.`
    },
    {
        question: `What does Jack Welch's 6 VS 9 theory entail?`,
        answer: `Fire the bottom 10%, and promote the top 10%. 
        Promote the 9's and fire the 6's (9's are superstars).`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is Indigenous Entrepreneurship?',
        answer: `Indigenous entrepreneurship focuses on new venture creation or the pursuit of economic opportunity or both, for the purpose of culturally viable and community-acceptable wealth creation. In other words, it is the creation, management and development of new ventures by Indigenous people for the benefit of Indigenous people`
    },
    {
        question: 'What are the 7 Sacred Grandfather Teachings from the lecture on Indigenous Entrepreneurship?',
        answer: `Truth, Wisdom, Love, Bravery, Respect, Honesty, and Humility.`
    },
    {
        question: `You are the Co-Founder of your own start-up venture with your friend from university. Integrating a strong corporate culture is very important for you; however, your friend may need some convincing. You argue to him that you want to create a positive work environment for your employees. List four (4) advantages of why it is important to have a strong corporate culture and how it would impact the business overall.`,
        answer: `Less oversight; people work harder and needs less supervision. 
        Lower employee turnover rate (thus, less cost for hiring). 
        Evangelical employees (happy, motivated employees). 
        Higher efficiency (more productive with their time). 
        People are dedicated to the success of the company. 
        Less sick days (less cost associated with health). 
        Easier to attract future employees. 
        Leads to more 9s and less 6s. 
        Less quality control issues. 
        Positive corporate culture is more productive (more 9s and less 6s). 
        Less turnover, therefore there will be less HR costs to hire and train new employees. Less sick days, therefore less cost associated with health and compensation.`
    },
    {
        question: 'Name the 5 KPIs that make up Pirate Metrics. Instead of defining them, show how Netflix might use each.',
        answer: `Acquisition: When customers first sign up for an account on Netflix and register for the 3-month free trial. 
        Activation: when using their free trial, customers begin watching and browsing through Netflix's extensive library of films/TV shows. 
        Retention: customers continue renewing their subscription plans and continue binge-watching their favourite shows/films. 
        Referral: when customers begin referring friends and family to sign up, or write reviews on Netflix-owned films/TV shows online, or through word-of-mouth marketing. 
        Revenue: the money that Netflix makes when a customer signs up for a monthly/annual subscription. `
    },
    {
        question: 'What are the main purposes for a Board of Directors versus a Board of Advisors?',
        answer: `The Board of Director's purpose is to represent the interests of the equity holders. The board is in charge of governance and represents the shareholders. 
        The Board of Advisors have no fiduciary duty to shareholders but their purpose is to offer a source of expert guidance and feedback.`
    },
    {
        question: 'What is creative destruction? Why do we need it?',
        answer: `Creative destruction describes the deliberate dismantling of established processes to make way for improved methods of doing business. We need creative destruction because it ultimately benefits society by giving customers more options to meet their needs — while also forcing organizations and their competitors to continually innovate and improve.`
    }
]

export default qbank;